Guide to the George Burbank Shattuck Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
George Burbank Shattuck papers
1919-1927
MS 1722
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The papers are comprised of diaries, clippings, photographs, and research materials. The bulk of the papers document Shattuck's involvement in a 1919-1920 anthropological expedition to East Africa, led by Leonard John Vanden Bergh. During this expedition, Shattuck kept a detailed travel diary and took many photographs which document native clothing, rituals, and culture. The collection also includes a less detailed diary of an expedition to Honduras in 1922.
Shattuck, George Burbank, 1869-1934
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator, 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
George Burbank Shattuck was born in Lowell, Massachusetts in 1869. He taught geology at John Hopkins University from 1897 to 1905 and at Vassar College from 1906 until his death in 1934. Shattuck also traveled extensively as a photographer for anthropological expeditions to locations including Africa, Central America, and the American West.
Scope and Contents
The papers are comprised of diaries, clippings, photographs, and research materials. The bulk of the papers document Shattuck's involvement in a 1919-1920 anthropological expedition to East Africa, led by Leonard John Vanden Bergh. During this expedition, Shattuck kept a detailed travel diary and took many photographs which document native clothing, rituals, and culture. The collection also includes a less detailed diary of an expedition to Honduras in 1922.
Ethnology -- Africa, East; Africa, East -- Description and travel; Africa, East -- Social life and customs; Photographs -- Africa, East; Shattuck, George Burbank, 1869-1934; Vanden Bergh, Leonard John
- Inventory
  - Bibliography [on Africa], undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Diaries
    - Africa expedition, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Honduras expedition, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photograph of George Burbank Shattuck (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs [Africa expedition], 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 9)
  - Translations [notes and interpretations of Swahili words and phrases], 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Writings [clippings of articles written for newspapers describing expedition to Africa], 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 11)